What we want to talk about now is the proper execution for our running backs and our quarterback while making the exchange in the pitch play.
The reason we call it the pitch play is because we use the pitch in order to get our speedy backs to the outside.
Earlier we used a sweep play which is a hand off.
This time we're going to use the pitch to get our man to the outside, hopefully to exploit the outside after we've set up the middle.
Our quarterback will take the snap and this time we're not going to fake to the fullback.
The fullback will go out and help with the blocking scheme.
Our quarterback will then open up wide and make a long pitch to the outside to the running back.
Our running back wants to make sure he doesn't go too wide after taking the pitch from the quarterback.
Then, he'll look to see where the defense is pinned in or the defense is kicked out and he'll get through the opening.
So, there are two different ways we can get to the outside.
One is to take the hand off.
But, right here, we used the pitch play.
That's when the quarterback will pitch it to our tailback so we can get outside and get up the field.